Ahmar Ali

Web Developer & Designer

Phone: 0307-433-4399

EMail: <u>easyload4free@gmail.com</u>

F-7 Third Floor Malhi plaza (18-M) M Block Model

Town

Lahore, Pakistan

Profile

I'm an enthusiastic and pro-active **Web Developer and Designer** who makes easy to use websites and applications by discovering how users *really* think.

As a professional I have developed more than 40 web based applications for various clients over past 3 years. During this period I have tried hard to learn new tools and technologies. Web development is my passion as well as profession.

Objective

I am seeking a new challenge in a progressive and customer-centric organization where I can make the most of my love of technology and my knowledge of user-centered design techniques.

Skills Summary

- PHP (4/5)
- MySQL
- Wordpress
- Magento
- Prestashop
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Bootstrap 3
- APIs: Twitter, Flickr, etc.

Employment History

ESP INTERACTIVE - Sr. PHP Developer SOLUTIONS

Dec 2011 – Jan 2015

Clients include: SAJALO,CHENONE, FAST CABLES, GABA OPTICS My responsibilities at ESP Interactive are to work together with junior developers and frontend developers in a team. At ESP we have wide array of clients and as a result I have learnt a lot about different Frameworks and Content Management Systems. Core job responsibilities are development of complete web applications from scratch as well as managing different projects and ensure their timely delivery by my team.

Freelancer.com -

Dec 2011 – Jan 2015

Clients include: TOMS Shoes, Cloud 9 Kicks, Catch It daily etc.

Web Developer / Designer

As a freelance web designer I have completed more than 20 projects related to web design and development on world's largest freelancing portal. My overall Rating is 4.7 out of 5.0 on Freelancer. The type of work ranges from development of new Websites from scratch to redesign and wordpress development. Wordpress is something that I have mastered on Freelancer.

Responsibilities and Achievements

Developed websites and applications using PHP and MySQL at the backend whilst building the frontend in **standards-compliant** XHTML, CSS and JavaScript.

- Replaced use of outdated Flash techniques with progressively-enhanced, accessible AJAX alternatives.
 Making use of framework such as jQuery where appropriate.
- Re-Designing of old-fashioned websites and converting them into Modern and attractive easy to use websites.
- Ensuring Cross Browser Compatibility by following W3C standards
- **Performance optimizing** websites through a combination of frontend, backend and server configuration techniques.
- Designing custom Wordpress themes for users according to their requirements
- Converting PSD Files to Pixel Perfect and Valid (X) HTML+CSS websites. Developing wordpress based e-commerce websites with features like Shopping Carts and Admin panels.
- Planning and implementing multivariate testing to evaluate hypotheses and improve conversion rates.

Education

BS(HONS)

Comsats Institute of IT Lahore Campus

2008 - 2013

Majors: Software Engineering, OOP, Algorithms, Database, Web Engineering

Interests

In my spare time I like to spend as much time as possible enjoying life travelling. I also enjoy reading and watching movies.

References

Will be furnished upon request.